Guide to the ACLU of Ohio Kent State Project Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Attorney Work Product, 1970-1980; Series II
  - Witness files, set 1, circa 1970-1978
    - Fassinger, Charles, 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Filo, John, 3 folders (Box 65)
    - Flesher, Okey, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Grace, Thomas, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Haberek, Judith (Box 66)
    - Hatfield, Robert (Box 66)
    - Herschler, William, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - Hinton, Lonnie (Box 66)
    - Jacobs, Sharon (Box 66)
    - James, Robert, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - Jones, Harry, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Kahler, Dean (Box 67)
    - Kamber, Gerald (Box 67)
    - Lewis, Joe (Box 67)
    - Locher, Paul (Box 68)
    - Love, Richard, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Lutey, Richard (Box 68)
    - MacKenzie, Donald (Box 68)
    - McGee, James, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - McManus, Mathew, Jr., 2 folders (Box 69)
    - McNees, Ronald (Box 69)
    - Martin, John, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Matson, Robert (Box 69)
    - Montgomery, William (Box 69)
    - Morris, Barry, 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Morris, Rudy (Box 70)
    - Mowrer, Larry, 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Myers, Ronnie (Box 70)
    - Naujoks, Paul (Box 70)
    - Perkins, William, 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Pickett, Robert (Box 71)
    - Pierce, James, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Pryor, Myron, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Reedy, A. L. (Box 71)
    - Repp, Russell, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Rhodes, James, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Robinson, Scott (Box 72)
    - Rogers, David (Box 72)
    - Ruffner, Howard (Box 72)
    - Ruffner, Howard (Box 73)
    - Russell, James (Box 73)
    - Satrom, LeRoy (Box 73)
    - Schott, Paul Allen (Box 73)
    - Shade, Richard (Box 73)
    - Shafer, Lawrence, 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Smith, Leon, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Snure, David (Box 74)
    - Snyder, James, 3 folders (Box 74)
    - Snyder, Richard (Box 74)
    - Srp, Raymond, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Stamps, Robert (Box 75)
    - Stevenson, Alexander, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Stiegemier, Rae Wagner, 2 folders (Box 76)
    - Thomas, Lloyd, 2 folders (Box 76)
    - Tople, Paul (Box 76)
    - White, Robert (Box 76)
    - Wrentmore, Doug (Box 76)
    - Zoller, Ralph, 2 folders (Box 117)
  - Witness files, set 2, circa 1970-1975
    - Ambler, Biddle, Canfora, Canterbury, Cleary, Cline, Darnell, Delaney, DelCorso, 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Fallon, Fassinger, Filo, Flesher, Gerstenslager, Grace, Herschler, James, Jones, Kahler, Lewis, Love, MacKenzie, Martin, 3 folders (Box 118)
    - Matson, McGee, McManus, Montgomery, Morris, Mowrer, Perkins, Pierce, Pryor, Repp, Rhodes, Robinson, Ruffner, Russell, Shafer, Smith, Snyder, Srp, Stamps, Stevenson, Thomas, Tople (did not testify; no sealed materials in this file), Wagner (Steigemeir), Wrentmore, Zoller, 4 folders (Box 119)
  - ACLU interviews
    - List of interviewees, partial, circa 1970 (Box 77)
    - Group 1 interviews, arranged alphabetically by interviewee and numbered 1-104, plus several unnumbered anonymous interviews, 5 folders, 1970 (Box 77)
    - Group 2 interviews, arranged alphanumerically (-A34, B1-B29, C1-C7), 3 folders, 1970 (Box 78)
      - Written transcripts of statements received by the ACLU, 1970 (Box 78)
      - Instructions and questions for ACLU testimony takers, 1970 (Box 78)
    - Group 3 interviews, no apparent order and some duplicate interviews in Groups 1 and 2, 2 folders, 1970 (Box 79)
    - Report forms, handwritten, providing information about the interviews, 4 folders, 1975 (Box 79)
    - Sharon Swanson statement, 1974 (Box 80)
    - Terri Sheridan report to Niki Schwartz about May 1970, 1971 (Box 80)
    - Notes from interview with Colin (Bob) Beichler, Kent Fire Department, circa 1975 (Box 80)
  - Potential contacts, circa 1975 (Box 80)
  - Drafts of letters from Anne Taylor, ACLU, to possible witnesses, 1975 (Box 80)
  - Investigative procedures, circa 1975 (Box 80)
  - Draft of questions for Frank Fassina, 1975 (Box 80)
  - Location of guardsmen, circa 1975 (Box 80)
  - Interview forms and maps, circa 1971-1975 (Box 80)
  - Notes on The Truth About Kent State by Peter Davies, circa 1973-1975 (Box 80)
  - List of 63 points/events, circa 1971-1975 (Box 80)
  - Testimony excerpts and notes, 3 folders, circa 1971-1975 (Box 80)
  - Testimony excerpts and notes, 9 folders, circa 1971-1975 (Box 81–82)
  - Notes on index cards, foldered as received in rubberbanded groups, circa 1971-1975 (Box 83–84)
  - ACLU news releases, fliers, and reports, 1970-1979 (Box 85)
  - Other interviews and first-hand accounts collected by the ACLU, 3 folders, circa 1970-1975 (Box 85)
  - Materials regarding controversy about KSU plans to build on the site of the the May 4th shootings, 1974-1977 (Box 85)
    - Oversize site development plan for KSU Health, Physical Education & Recreation Facility, Richard Fleischman Architects, Inc., 1977 February 18 (Box 189)
  - Photocopies of handwritten notes, circa 1970 (Box 85)
  - Defense of Kent State students charged with curfew violations, 1970-1971 (Box 85)
- Background Materials, Circa 1960-1979; Series III
  This series consists of material gathered from a variety of sources, such as investigative agencies, the media, Kent State University, and other parties with an interest in events relating to the May 4, 1970 shootings, including James Michener and Peter Davies.Â Much of the material is not arranged beyond the creator level, where the individual or organization is known. Background materials were primarily used for research and legal strategy development by attorneys and their supporting staff.
  While some documents produced by investigative agencies were required to be redacted by a March 12, 1979 court order issued by Judge William Thomas, the items in this collection were deemed acceptable for release by staff and the general counsel of the ACLU of Ohio in July 2006.
  Included at the end of this series is a collection of audiotapes, most marked with a last name.Â The origin of the tapes is unknown.Â Other audiotapes may be found with other trial exhibits in Series I.
  This series is arranged primarily by the author or organization responsible for producing or supplying the accumulated materials.
  - FBI 302 forms (reports of interviews with a witness by FBI agents), redacted photocopies obtained either through public records requests or the legal discovery process, 1970
    - Set 1, unclear for what purpose volume-based arrangement was created and whereabouts of volumes 5-6 unknown
      - Volumes 1-4, 4 folders (Box 87)
      - Volumes 7-10, 4 folders (Box 88)
      - Volumes 11-13 and 1 unnumbered volume, 4 folders (Box 89)
    - Set 2, probably numbered and used by ACLU legal staff
      - 1-199, 2 folders (Box 98)
      - 200-499, 3 folders (Box 99)
      - 500-737, 4 folders (Box 100)
  - Kent City Police Department daily patrol phone and radio logs (incomplete), 3 folders, 1970-1972 (Box 90)
  - Kent State University Police Department daily patrol phone and radio logs, 1970 (Box 90)
  - Bureau of Criminal Investigation charts of movements, 1970 May 4 (Box 90)
  - Adjutant General's Department daily staff journal, Ft. Hayes and Medina, Ohio, 2 folders, 1970 (Box 90)
  - Ohio National Guard
    - Logs, 2 folders, 1970 May 2 and May 5 (Box 91)
    - Firing incident reports, 1970 May 4 (Box 91)
  - Ohio State Highway Patrol newsclippings files, 1970-1971 (Box 91)
  - U.S. Departement of Justice summary of FBI report, circa 1970 (Box 91)
  - Investigative agency materials
    - President's Commission on Campus Unrest hearings
      - Transcripts, 3 folders, 1970 August 18-19 (Box 91)
      - Transcripts, 2 folders, 1970 August 20-21 (Box 92)
      - Transcripts, copy marked Plaintiff's Exhibit 45, 5 folders, 1970 August 18-21 (Box 101)
  - Military and law enforcement policies, regulations, and training manuals relating to control of civil disturbances, 6 folders, circa 1960-1970 (Box 92–93)
  - Kent State University Police Department
    - Materials produced pursuant to 1975 subpoena, includes index, 11 folders, circa 1970-1978 (Box 94)
    - Intelligence unit reports, incomplete
      - B1-B127, 1971 (Box 94)
      - S3-S394, 1971 (Box 95)
      - A1-A99, 1972 (Box 95)
      - Other reports, 1970 (Box 95)
  - Ohio National Guard
    - Disturbance control training, circa 1969-1970 (Box 95)
    - State Operations Plan, 1970 (Box 95)
    - Daily staff journal (Ft. Hayes, Greensburg, Medina, Akron, Kent State), 4 folders, 1970 April 29-May 5 (Box 95)
    - Other documents related to Kent State disturbances, 1970-1971 (Box 96)
    - Photographs, 1970 (Box 96)
  - Kent State University
    - KSU Archives, notes about and photocopies of materials in the archives, 10 folders, circa 1971-1975 (Box 96)
    - "The Events of May 1-4, 1970 at Kent State University," minority report of the Commission on KSU Violence, 2 folders, circa 1971 (Box 96)
    - Interviews and statements used by the Commission on KSU Violence, 1970 (Box 96)
    - Materials relating to KSU violence produced by the University, 3 folders, circa 1963-1978 (Box 97)
      - Restricted (Box 102)
  - Photographs, circa 1970-1975
    - Arranged by photographer
      - John Darnell, oversize folder (Box 187)
      - Howard Ruffner; Marcia L. Adams; Charles Ayers; Bruce Barton; Beverly Knowles Burger; Sandra Martin Bullock; John Darnell; Jack Davis; David Eads; John Filo; Howard Fisher; Michael Glaser; Richard C. Harris, Jr.; Lloyd D. Heilman; 17 folders (Box 103)
      - Kent State University Police Department; Donn Kevern; John Kevern; Lori Legge; William Ling; William J. McGuire III; Ronald McNees; Douglas Moore; Gregory Moore; Timothy Nighswawner; Terrance B. Norman; Timothy Oleski; James Peck; Don Roese; Deborah Ross; Stephen G. Scheuler; Larry Shank; Victor Sloan; Daniel Smith; Patricia Sorse; Rae Wagner Steigemeier; Michael Stein; Jerome Stoklas; James Thomas; Paul Tople; 26 folders (Box 104)
      - Harold C. Walker; Terry Wilson; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Vacant campus scenes, views from parking lot across practice field (Box 105)
    - Unidentified photographers (many are duplicates from photographs arranged by photographer), 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Identification of National Guard troops (Box 105)
    - Plaintiffs' exhibits 3004-37006 (Box 105)
    - Plaintiffs' exhibits 37007-54015 (Box 106)
  - News clippings, pamphlets, and articles, originals and photocopies
    - 1970s (Box 106)
    - 1970s-2000, 3 folders (Box 107)
    - Unsorted materials, 16 folders, circa 1970-1979 (Box 110)
  - Books and periodicals
    - The National Guardsman 70, 1970 June (Box 110)
    - Hensley, Thomas R. and Jerry M. Lewis, Kent State and May 4th: A Social Science Perspective, 1978 (Box 110)
    - Stang, Alan, Kent State: Proof to Save the Guardsmen, 1974 June (Box 110)
    - Taylor, Stuart, et al, Violence at Kent State, May 1-4, 1970: The Students' Perspective, 1971 (Box 110)
  - Printed ephemera relating to Kent State violence and aftermath, circa 1970-1978 (Box 108)
  - Published and unpublished articles and essays, 1969-1977 (Box 108)
  - National Archives materials, photocopies (Box 108)
    - Interviews, circa 1970
      - A-B, 4 folders (Box 108)
      - C-S, 9 folders (Box 109)
      - T-Y, 3 folders (Box 111)
    - Correspondence, Kent State, 1970 (Box 111)
    - Memoranda and other materials regarding witnesses, circa 1970 (Box 111)
  - Ohio General Assembly bills after May 4th, 1970-1972 (Box 111)
  - Davies, Peter, "An Appeal to the United State Department of Justice for an Immediate and Thorough Investigation of the Circumstances Surrounding the Shootings at Kent State University, May, 1970," 2 copies signed by author, 1971 June 21 (Box 111)
  - Notes and reports relating to various aspects of the Kent State violence, 2 folders, 1970-1979 (Box 112)
  - Photographs, photocopies, 3 folders, 1970 (Box 112)
  - Kent 25 files, clippings, legal documents, and notes relating to the secret grand jury indictment of 25 individuals, many students, in relation to the violence at Kent State, 4 folders, 1970-1971 (Box 112)
  - Kent 25 files, 10 folders, 1970-1971 (Box 113)
  - Press conference transcripts, press releases, and media interview transcripts, non-ACLU, 1970-1978 (Box 114)
  - Book manuscript or report, portion (p. 27-272), circa 1970-1975 (Box 114)
  - Background material, unsorted
    - Photographs, circa 1970-1978 (Box 114)
    - Memoranda, witness lists, reports, and other materials, 4 folders, circa 1968-1971 (Box 114)
  - James Michener materials
    - Correspondence and other materials regarding consulting Kent State materials in the Michener papers at Library of Congress, circa 1974 (Box 115)
    - Kent, Michener index, circa 1974 (Box 115)
    - Photocopies of materials obtained from the National Archives, 7 folders, circa 1970-1971 (Box 115)
    - Photocopies of materials obtained from the National Archives, 4 folders, circa 1970-1971 (Box 116)
  - Audio materials, source unknown, titles transcribed from writing on tape cases, often barely legible, circa 1970-1975
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Beverly Knowles [restricted], audiocassette (Box 131)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 131U)
    - 1. James McGee, 2. Howard Fisher, 3. Bruce Lenox [restricted], audiocassette (Box 132)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 132U)
    - 1. Cliff Buchosh, 2. Dennis Holonak, 3. Varner Scott, 4. Jerry Yocum, 5. Rita Rosenberg, 6. Dr. Jos Ewing, 7. Christopher Jerman, 8. Tim Chitwood [restricted], audiocassette (Box 133)
      - Use copy, 2 (Box 133Ua–133Ub)
        General
        Boxes 133Ua and 133Ub list Rosenberg, Ewing, Jerman, and Chitwood on disc label. Buchosh and Holonak are not listed on disc label, although mentioned on original disc in finding aid.
    - 1. Michael Turkoc, 2. Beverly Knowles, 3. Ralph Zoller, 4. Okey Flesher [restricted], audiocassette (Box 134)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 134U)
    - 3. Bruce Lenox, 4. Dan Rossi, 5. Roger Maas, 6. Luckia Perry [restricted], audiocassette (Box 135)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 135U)
    - 1. Gordon Biddle, 2. Robert Foley, 3. Rodney Biddle, 4. Beverly Knowles [restricted], audiocassette (Box 136)
    - 9. Dr. Robert White [restricted], audiocassette (Box 137)
      - Use copy, 2 (Box 137Ua–137Ub)
    - 1. Dr. Robt White, 2. Chester Williams, 3. Dr. Richard Dunn, 4. Mr. Robert Dix [restricted], audiocassette (Box 138)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 138U)
    - 4. Okey Flesher, 5. Joseph Lewis, 6. Steven Boss, 7. Bruce King [restricted], audiocassette (Box 139)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 139U)
    - Richard Schreiber, Jerome Stoklas [restricted], audiocassette (Box 140)
    - Michener [restricted], 3 audiocassettes (Box 141–143)
    - Kamber [restricted], audiocassette (Box 144)
    - Jerry Persky, Nancy Rogers (Dykes) [restricted], audiocassette (Box 145)
    - Bev Burger (Knowles) [restricted], audiocassette (Box 146)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 146U)
    - Mike Delaney, Russel Fackler [restricted], audiocassette (Box 147)
    - Russel Fackler, Harry Montgomery [restricted], audiocassette (Box 148)
      Original audiotapes and videotapes, as well as preservation masters and duplicating masters, may not be played. Consult a reference archivist to determine availability of a use copy or the process required to generate a use copy.
      - Use copy, Only Montgomery is listed on use copy disc label. (Box 148U)
    - Stu Feldstein [restricted], audiocassette (Box 149)
    - Heffelf... [restricted], audiocassette (Box 150)
    - Judith Brennan (Young) [restricted], audiocassette (Box 151)
    - Frank Surace, Tim Rily [restricted], audiocassette (Box 152)
    - Calkins, Wm. Wuldman [restricted], audiocassette (Box 153)
    - Woodring, Whipple [restricted], audiocassette (Box 154)
    - Charles Brill [restricted], audiocassette (Box 155)
    - Zvara [restricted], audiocassette (Box 156)
    - Zahler, Test [restricted], audiocassette (Box 157)
    - Heffelf..., Zahler [restricted], audiocassette (Box 158)
    - Paula Tucker [restricted], audiocassette (Box 159)
    - Smythe [restricted], audiocassette (Box 160)
    - Smythe, Hupplebee [restricted], audiocassette (Box 161)
    - Paul Schott [restricted], audiocassette (Box 162)
    - Arthsall [restricted], audiocassette (Box 163)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 163U)
    - LaChance [restricted], audiocassette (Box 164)
    - Tim Masterson [restricted], audiocassette (Box 165)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 165U)
    - Tape 5 [restricted], audiocassette (Box 166)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 166U)
    - Jim Woodring [restricted], audiocassette (Box 167)
    - Unlabeled [restricted], audiocassette (Box 168)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 168U)
    - Nixon [restricted], audiocassette (Box 169)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 169U)
    - X-13, X-14, X-15, and X-16 [restricted], audiocassette (Box 170)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 170U)
    - X-31 [restricted], audiocassette (Box 171)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 171U)
    - SJR open [restricted], audiocassette (Box 172)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 172U)
    - WEA 5-27-70 (Plaintiff's Exhibit 50029) [restricted], audiocassette (Box 173)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 173U)
    - Dee Titchenal/#50027 May 4th(Shots) [restricted], 1; Duration 1 hour, 33 minutes, 49 seconds; Approximately first minute of side A is blank. High Amount of Buzz on tape. High Amount of Hum on tape. Recording distorted at times. (Box 174)
    - Jerry Lewis [restricted], audiocassette (Box 175)
    - Conte and officers [restricted], audiocassette (Box 176)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 176U)
    - WKSU, White and Matson [restricted], audiocassette (Box 177)
    - WHLO tape/Paskoff - begin [restricted], audiocassette (Box 178)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 178U)
    - Ted Joy [restricted], audiocassette (Box 179)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 179U)
    - Governor Rhodes press conference, 2 audiocassettes, 1970 May 3 (Box 180–181)
      - Use copy, 2 (Box 180U–181U)
    - Carol and Bob Sacherman interview with Marvin Avroms, 1974 August 20; audiocassette (Box 182)
    - Jill Zimmerman, R. Margolis, Barry Morris, William Resch, Robt. Hatfield, John Koury [restricted], audiocassette (Box 183)
    - Scobie, James Snyder [restricted], audiocassette (Box 184)
    - Rest of Williams-White [restricted], audiocassette (Box 185)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 185U)
    - James Pierce, Canterbury, Perkins, Pekanik, Hirst, Whitmer [restricted], audiocassette (Box 186)
      - Use copy, 2 (Box 186Ua–186Ub)